<thing><id>514</id><title>*Updated* Medium Format Camera</title><author>langfordw</author><description>I've been meaning to make a printable camera for a while now but I\'ve found it difficult to get all the dimensions nice and to have it be printable. Hopefully this one is both printable and just generally cool. Because the Makerbot, or any  3D printer for that matter, isn't the greatest at making pinholes, this design assumes you can make your own out of tinfoil or a soda can or whatever and attach it to the front. It uses a very simple/primitive shutter mechanism where you just lift up the front tab for however long you want to expose the film. The back is curved to give a cool distorted affect hopefully. Of course this could be fixed and made straight but where's the fun in that? The top just simply rests on top so you'll probably want to tape that down once you load your film.It uses 120 (medium format film) and will probably be need to be loaded in the dark.I'm sure it'll have some problems but the idea of being able to print your own camera was too cool to pass up.**Holga Shutter and Lens Update**I just now realized how awesome and easy it would be to attach the entire holga shutter and lens assembly to the front. For those of you unfamiliar with the Holga it is basically just a really hackable plastic camera. (http://www.lomography.com/holga/)I attached an updated version of the bottom case with a mount for the assembly. All you need to do is grab an old Holga, take off the assembly with the two screws and re-screw it onto your newly printed custom camera. Now you have a pretty much fully functional camera with an actual shutter and lens.I'm not sure about the new bottomcase's print-ablility. If it has problems I attached a flat holga attachment piece that can printed seperately and be screwed onto the front of the camera.One thing to note... the optics might be a little funky because of the film's distance from the lens. should be interesting...</description></thing>